<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-01T15:06:38-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Indira Tatikola</title><subtitle>Hi! I’m Indira and I’m studying computer science at the Georgia Institute of Technology.  My areas of interest are computer vision, graphics, and machine learning and their applications in social media. Feel free to reach out through any platform! </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Balmain Mens’ FW 24 Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/01/15/Balmain-Mens-FW.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Balmain Mens’ FW 24 Review" /><published>2024-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/01/15/Balmain-Mens-FW</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/01/15/Balmain-Mens-FW.html">&lt;p&gt;    Paris Fashion Week 2024 featured some amazing collections with many critics remarking on the return of true haute couture - art as fashion. Pieces were bold, vibrant, and meaningful across the board. However, Balmain Mens’ FW 24, designed by the young breakthrough Olivier Rouesting, was a standout.  &lt;!--more--&gt; Last year, Rouesting revealed that he had been badly burned during a fireplace explosion in his own home. He had kept the incident private for a long time, and his return invoked a newfound sense of purpose. In fact, his new braids almost made him unrecognizable when he came out at the end of the show. I found the show to be an unabashed homage to African royalty and modern Afro-European culture, celebrating the work of modern African art and revealing the impact of African creatives on global fashion. This show was defined by coats, vibrant colors, and royal futurism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Black_Bag&quot; alt=&quot;None&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    The most powerful sequence in the show to me were the black and metallic gold looks. The sequence began abruptly with the structured, reflective coat. The long coat’s rigidity and simple structure felt like something a fashionable CP-30 would wear in the best way possible. This is a coat meant for the night, an ode to being the shining light of royalty in the room. The sharp corners of the shoulders and abrupt circular ending to the sleeve furthers the roboticism. All in all, I find it to be an exciting step towards pure futuristic style. The pairing with faded black denim works, although the jeans are of a certain tasteless style. I’ll chalk it up to the specific connotation this jean style has in American culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;image&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Overall, the gold motif was a strong example of celebrating African greatness. I immediately think of Mansa Musa - the African king who was at one point the richest man in the world due to his hefty collection of gold. In the eastern world, gold is most definitely the greatest symbol of wealth though it has largely left the gaze of western idyllism. The golden durag and chains are also odes to the unique and unmatched significance of gold as a symbol of power and royalty in African culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;image&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    The vibrant orange, pink, yellow and black patent leather jacket and then shiny leather bag immediately caught my eye. The splotching design reminded me of the eye itself actually - a cornea or on another note, a celestial supernova. It radiates power and an all-knowing existentialism, though I wish the jackets colors were as vibrant as the bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;image&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Most striking of all however was the facial sequence. The show opened with the long coat featuring an AI-generated face created with what seems to be rhinestones. This is an ode to the technological aspect of futurism that simply cannot be ignored, Rouesting is acknowledging the dominance of artificial intelligence in all aspects of life. The use of rhinestones creates a pixelated effect, adding onto the illusion that the pieces are made of actual screens. The black and white eye specifically reminds me of the type of image you would see in a 2000s era girls’ internet makeup game - it’s almost Bratz-like. In this way, Rouesting preserves the youthful streetwear roots of Balmain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;image&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    I think the underlying reason I was drawn to this show is because of its outstanding progressiveness. I truly believe that Olivier Rouesting understands the future and I respect that he is using his influence and genius to propel his people and culture to the forefront of the future. African royalty, digital supremacy, artificial intelligence in art - Rouesting is a master of representing the here and now. He defines a generation and I cannot wait to see how this collection manifests in the mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">    Paris Fashion Week 2024 featured some amazing collections with many critics remarking on the return of true haute couture - art as fashion. Pieces were bold, vibrant, and meaningful across the board. However, Balmain Mens’ FW 24, designed by the young breakthrough Olivier Rouesting, was a standout.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project #1: Personal Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/12/15/Project-1-Personal-Site.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project #1: Personal Website" /><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/15/Project-#1-Personal-Site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/12/15/Project-1-Personal-Site.html">&lt;p&gt;    In November, I felt an urge to put my programming capabilities to the test and start developing. As I delved into other people’s personal projects to look for inspiration and guidance, I felt overwhelmed with where to start.  &lt;!--more--&gt; I would get discouraged by how advanced other people were, how many various platforms and languages they knew, and the amount of time many of my peers had already spent. It just felt like it was impossible to catch up - but everyone has to start somewhere. Instead of wallowing, I needed to create something that would encourage me to continue creating. I thought, “Everyone seems to have a personal site where they put their projects, which means that 1) I can create a site, and 2) it’ll look pretty dumb if there are no projects on it, so I’ll be forced to keep going.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    And here’s the final product - welcome to my site! Here’s a little bit about it. I’m hosting the site on Github Pages and used Github’s static site builder, Jekyll, for the general HTML format. I chose Jekyll because it’s meant to be used specifically for blog-style websites. I copied over the default CSS theme, “minima”, into my local folders and made edits from there to personalize the design. I tried to mimic the Apple theme a bit with rounded edges and a simple color scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    I’m using Google Analytics to keep track of site data by copying a site tag onto each HTML page. From my analytics dashboard, I can view page-by-page insights on how many people are viewing the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Pretty simple start, can’t wait to keep experimenting :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">    In November, I felt an urge to put my programming capabilities to the test and start developing. As I delved into other people’s personal projects to look for inspiration and guidance, I felt overwhelmed with where to start.</summary></entry></feed>